# **Tanmay Singh**

tanmaysinghx.netlify.app | LinkedIn | Github

Email: tanmaysinghx@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 9511993316

# FRONT END DEVELOPER -UI/UX

Versatile Front-end Developer with 3 years of experience in JavaScript and related frameworks and libraries. Skilled in building responsive web applications and maintaining reusable codebases. Experienced in all phases of the application lifecycle, from development and deployment to support..

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** : JavaScript

Frameworks : Angular 17, Angular 15

**CSS Libraries** : Material UI, Bootstrap 5, Tailwind CSS

Unit Testing : Jasmine and Karma
 Version Control : Bitbucket, Github, Git, Jira
 Code Quality : SonarQube, Veracode

Other Familiar Technologies: Java, SpringBoot, CI/CD Pipeline using Docker and Git actions/Jenkins, AWS - EC2

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Systems EngineerSeptember 2023 – PresentTata Consultancy Services LimitedGurugramSenior Systems EngineerOctober 2022 – July 2023Infosys LimitedPuneSystems EngineerJuly 2021 – October 2022

Infosys Limited Pune

**Systems Engineer Trainee**Infosys Limited

February 2021 – June 2021

Mysore

#### **PROJECT**

# **Deal Management System**

November-2023 to Present

American International Group Inc

- Led the migration of a comprehensive Quote and Bind application, a core component of the Deal Management System, from JSP to Angular 17
- Utilized Angular Material UI and Bootstrap to design intuitive and responsive user interfaces, enhancing user experience.
- Migrated application led to a 40 percent reduction in maintenance efforts and faster implementation of new features.
- Played a crucial role in modernizing the organization's Deal Management System, positioning it for future growth and scalability.
- Implemented various performance enhancements, resulting in a significant reduction in page load times and improved application responsiveness.

## **Investment Management Application**

August-2021 to July-2023

Vanguard Ltd

- Working on Test driven development using Angular 15 framework.
- Involved in converting existing legacy application to modern application.
- · Worked on Micro Frontend Architecture implementation using Single Spa.
- Development of good quality code by adhering best practices and sonarQube guidelines.
- Unit testing of UI components using Jasmine-Karma.
- Documentations on confluence and task management in Jira.

#### **EDUCATION**

## SRM Institute of Science and Technology